Finding aid to Alumnae Oral History Project collection CA.MS.00301
Smith College Archives
Alumnae Oral History Project collection
2010-2018
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.00301
207 Gigabytes (Transcripts, video, and audio files)
5.25 linear feet (15 containers)
The Alumnae Oral History Project collection is comprised of oral histories conducted with Smith College alumnae during reunion weekends from 2010 to 2017. The project was funded by the President's Office and the College Archives and coordinated by Kelly Anderson. Students from the Archives Concentration and Anderson's classes in oral history conducted the interviews. The collection contains video recordings, transcripts, and project records.
Biographical / Historical
The Alumnae Oral History Project was funded by the President's Office and the College Archives and coordinated by Kelly Anderson. Students from the Archives Concentration and Anderson's classes in oral history conducted the interviews with alumnae over reunion weekend in May from 2010 to 2017 in the Alumnae Gymnasium, the home of the Smith College Archives.
Interviews were 30 minutes long, on average, and were taped by videographer Kate Geis and Rebecca Rideout, as well as student interviewers. Narrators were asked to reflect on their reasons for choosing Smith, key experiences during their time on campus, significant political and social issues that marked their time at Smith and the impact a Smith education has had on their lives and careers.
Scope and Contents
The Alumnae Oral History Project constists of interviews conducted by oral history students with alumnae retuirning to Smith for reunion weekends between the years 2010 and 2017. Alumnae were interviewed in the Alumnae Gym where the college's archives were housed until 2017. They were asked to reflect on their college experience at Smith in interviews that lasted approximately 30 minutes. The collection consists of video tapes and transcripts as well as digistized versions of these interviews. Materials concerning the overall project are included in these records.
Interviews conducted from 2010 to 2015 are available on the Smith College Libraries website
Conditions Governing Access
Several of the oral histories in this collection have restrictions on access. Please see the notes attached to an individual interview for information about restrictions that apply to it.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Smith College Alumnae Oral History Project collection is comprised of oral histories conducted with alumnae during reunion weekends beginning in 2010 and sponsored by Smith Special Collections. This is a continuing collection.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.
Existence and Location of Copies
Interviews conducted from 2010 to 2015 are available on the Smith College Libraries website: https://libraries.smith.edu/node/43329.
African American women college students; College students; Gay college students -- United States -- History; Smith College -- History -- Sources; Smith College -- Students -- History -- Sources; Universities and colleges--Alumni and alumnae--History--Sources; Videotapes; Electronic records; Oral histories
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2010), Accession 2012-A-0026
  - Katherine Evans (Class of 2000) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    Conditions Governing Access
    This interview is available for research without restriction. No online access.
    Scope and Contents
    In this oral history, Katharine Evans discusses her decision to attend Smith, her experiences playing sports (field hockey, lacrosse, and squash) and living in Lamont House, and her study of biology (major) and chemistry (minor). She also describes her life after Smith—working at a nonprofit, attending graduate school, and her current career as a physical therapist.
    - Video interview with Katherine Evans
    - Transcript of interview with Katherine Evans (Box 1)
  - Clara Fang (Class of 2005) interviewed by Rachel Dean, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Clara Fang discusses her involvement with MassPIRG, working to oppose drilling in the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, interning at the Environmental Science and Policy Program, working with the student group Gaia, and starting a student organization called Clean Energy for Smith. Fang also talks about living in Park House, going abroad at Oxford University, her experiences as an English major, racial tensions on campus, the impact of the September 11th attacks on Smith, and her life after Smith, attending the University of Utah and Yale, and working as an environmental professional.
    - Video interview with Clara Fang
    - Transcript of interview with Clara Fang (Box 1)
  - Ginna Rohan Hall (Class of 1985) interviewed by Rachel Dean, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    This interview is available for research without restriction.
    In this oral history, Ginna Rohan Hall discusses growing up in Northampton and how that impacted her time at Smith, her experiences living in Baldwin, Northrop, and Morris, and her work as a psychology major. She also describes issues of diversity at Smith, and the impact that Smith has had on her life.
    - Video interview with Gina Rohan Hall
    - Transcript of interview with Gina Rohan Hall (Box 1)
  - Melissa Homestead (Class of 1985) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Melissa Homestead discusses living in Lawrence House, Wilder House, and Parsons Annex, her experiences as an English major and her thesis on Willa Cather, and her participation in music clubs and the Lesbian Alliance. Homestead also describes issues surrounding sexuality and lesbianism, the Hover House controversy, incidents of homophobia and tensions between heterosexual and homosexual students, the Feminist and Lesbian Alumnae of Smith College (FLASC) group, and her experiences at the University of Pennsylvania.
    - Video interview with Melissa Homestead
    - Transcript of interview with Melissa Homestead (Box 1)
  - Erin Joslyn (Class of 1990) interviewed by Rachel Dean, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Erin Joslyn discusses her involvement with the student publication The Greer Age, her experiences living in Hopkins, studying in Cambridge, England, and her work as an art history major. Josyln also describes the overall campus atmosphere, including issues of diversity and tensions between heterosexual and homosexual students. Finally, Joslyn talks about the societal difficulties and pressures that women face, what it feels like to be back at her Smith reunion, and who she has become since Smith — working as an art historian, owning an antiques business, and working as a writer on several different projects.
    - Video interview with Erin Joslyn
    - Transcript of interview with Erin Joslyn (Box 1)
  - Jean Kahler (Class of 2000) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Jean Kahler discusses her decision to come to Smith, her experiences living in Hubbard House, her work as a theater major, her process of coming out as a lesbian, and the overall atmosphere surrounding homosexuality.
    - Video interview with Jean Kahler
    - Transcript of interview with Jean Kahler (Box 1)
  - Katie McCarthy (Class of 2005) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Katie McCarthy discusses her work as a psychology and education double major, and her involvement with SGA and Senate, Healthy Heads (a mental health support group), and Residence Life. She also describes the racial tensions on campus and her experiences while abroad in Australia.
    - Video interview with Katie McCarthy
    - Transcript of interview with Katie McCarthy (Box 1)
  - Christine Merrill (Class of 2005) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Christine Merrill discusses her experiences on the crew team and the swim team, her time abroad in Geneva, Switzerland and travels in Europe, and her work as an art history major.
    - Video interview with Christine Merrill
    - Transcript of interview with Christine Merrill (Box 1)
  - Mariceleste Miller (Class of 1990) interviewed by Rachel Dean, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Mariceleste Miller discusses her experiences living in Morris House and Park House, her involvement with theater, and her work as a biology major and math minor. She also describes the general campus climate and atmosphere (including racial tensions), Helen Caldicott's commencement address, and her current work with the Smith admissions office in Baltimore, Maryland.
    - Video interview with Mariceleste Miller
    - Transcript of interview with Mariceleste Miller (Box 1)
  - Nina Moe (Class of 2001) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Nina Moe describes her experience coming to Smith from Europe (Norway and Poland), her coming out process, her work in the music department at Smith, and her current career as a musician. She also describes the campus atmosphere, including racial tensions and issues around sexual and gender diversity.
    - Video interview with Nina Moe
    - Transcript of interview with Nina Moe (Box 1)
  - KP Perkins (Class of 1985) interviewed by Rachel Dean, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, KP Perkins discusses why she decided to attend Smith, her involvement in extracurricular activities (including student activism), and her work as an Afro-American studies and French double major. She also describes the general campus atmosphere, particularly in regards to race, and her opinion of President Conway.
    - Video interview with KP Perkins
    - Transcript of interview with KP Perkins (Box 1)
  - Sara Pic (Class of 2000) interviewed by Rachel Dean, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Sara Pic describes her involvement with activism at Smith (including her association with the Lesbian Avengers and working for transgender student rights), living in Hubbard House, her experiences abroad in Russia, her work as a Russian Civilization major and with the Study of the Women and Gender, and her decision to go to Northeastern Law School.
    - Video interview with Sara Pic
    - Transcript of interview with Sara Pic (Box 1)
  - Sindhu Revuluri (Class of 2000) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Sindhu Revuluri discusses her decision to attend Smith, her experiences living in King House, her participation in the Student Government Association and music clubs, her coming out experience, and her summer abroad in Ghana. She also describes the general campus atmosphere and incidents concerning conservative Smith students, and her graduate school experiences at Princeton University.
    - Video interview with Sindhu Revuluri
    - Transcript of interview with Sindhu Revuluri (Box 1)
  - Melanie Rosen (Class of 2000) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Melanie Rosen discusses her decision to attend Smith, her experiences living in Wilson House, working as a Gold Key guide, participating on the crew team, her work as a French studies major and Afro-American studies minor, and her time abroad in Paris and West Africa. She also describes the overall campus atmosphere and her experiences as a Fulbright scholar after Smith.
    - Video interview with Melanie Rosen
    - Transcript of interview with Melanie Rosen (Box 1)
  - Jess Rowe (Class of 1997) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Jess Rowe explains her decision to come to Smith, her work as a Painting and English double major, her coming out process and relationship with her partner, and her experiences after leaving Smith.
    - Video interview with Jess Rowe
    - Transcript of interview with Jess Rowe (Box 1)
  - Brittain Skinner (Class of 2000) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Brittain Skinner describes why she came to Smith, her experiences studying at the University of Kentucky for two semesters and how it compared to Smith, her work as an English major and biology minor, her experiences living in Wilson House and her role as house president, and her involvement with the Helen Hills Chapel Protestant group. She also explains what it has meant to her to be a Smith graduate.
    - Video interview with Brittain Skinner
    - Transcript of interview with Brittain Skinner (Box 1)
  - Meghan Tierney (Class of 2000) interviewed by Rachel Dean, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Meghan Tierney discusses her experiences living in Lamont House, playing on the volleyball and softball teams, acting as the Vice President of her class, and working in the Alumnae House. She also describes her time at the Smithsonian program, her work as an art history and archaeology minor, and her life after Smith.
    - Video interview with Meghan Tierney
    - Transcript of interview with Meghan Tierney (Box 1)
  - Ana Tolentino (Class of 1985) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Ana Tolentino discusses how she decided to attend Smith, her departure from Smith to attend the University of Wisconsin in Madison for a semester, and her return to Smith. Tolentino also describes her time at Smith, including her experiences as an art history major and archaeology minor, and the atmosphere of the early 1980s.
    - Video interview with Ana Tolentino
    - Transcript of interview with Ana Tolentino (Box 1)
  - Sarah Trabucchi (Class of 2000) interviewed by Maggie Kraus, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Sarah Trabucchi discusses her experiences living in Lamont House, participating in the theater department and working with the Northampton High School theater program, and her work as an American Studies major. She also describes the 1996 Presidential election, gay rights, and the general campus atmosphere.
    - Video interview with Sarah Trabucchi
    - Transcript of interview with Sarah Trabucchi (Box 1)
  - Sophia Wallace (Class of 2000) interviewed by Rachel Dean, 2010 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Sophia Wallace discusses her involvement with WOZQ radio, FIRE (Feminist Intercultural Revolutionary Encounter), PULSE (an art collective), rugby, and various activist activities. She also describes her appreciation of President Simmons, her experiences in Sessions House, her time studying abroad in Ghana, and the general atmosphere of Smith, particularly in regards to diversity.
    - Video interview with Sophia Wallace
    - Transcript of interview with Sophia Wallace (Box 1)
  - Mary Werner (Class of 1985) interviewed by Rachel Dean, 2010 May 14; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Mary Werner explains why she chose to attend Smith, her experiences with Student Senate, tutoring local children, and her work as a psychology major. She also describes the general campus atmosphere and diversity, her opinions on President Conway, and her life after Smith.
    - Video interview with Mary Werner
    - Transcript of interview with Mary Werner (Box 1)
  - Original videotapes and preservation master DVDs, 2010; 0.5 linear feet (1 container) (Box 2)
    General
    Original av materials are restricted; digital copies are available for research.
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2011), Accession 2012-A-0026
  - Judith Silverman Ames (Class of 1961) interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Judith Silverman Ames discusses why she chose to attend Smith, her experiences living in Clark House, her participation playing on various sports teams and with musical groups. Ames also describes the campus atmosphere, the lack of diversity, the benefits of same-sex education, her post-Smith experiences living abroad in Mexico and Japan, and her various career choices.
    - Video interview with Judith Silverman Ames
    - Transcript of interview with Judith Silverman Ames (Box 3)
  - Sandra Baldonado (Class of 1956) interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Sandy Baldonado describes the overall campus atmosphere, her experiences living in Hubbard House, participating in sports and theater, designing her own international relations major, her work at the CIA, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
    - Video interview with Sandra Baldonado
    - Transcript of interview with Sandra Baldonado (Box 3)
  - Adele Baydin (Class of 1951) interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    This interview is available for research. No online access.
    In this oral history, Adele Baydin discusses her experiences living in Chapin House, what it was like being a Jewish student at Smith, her travels in Europe, and why she decided to leave Smith after her sophomore year.
    - Video interview with Adele Baydin
    - Transcript of interview with Adele Baydin (Box 3)
  - Elaine Bennett (Class of 1981) interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Elaine Bennett discusses her initial reactions to Smith, her experiences living in Ziskind House, her work as a theater major. Bennett also describes the dialogues surrounding feminism during the late 1970s and early 80s, the lesbian community on campus, and what it feels like returning to campus for reunion.
    - Video interview with Elaine Bennett
    - Transcript of interview with Elaine Bennett (Box 3)
  - Marianne Bickerton (Class of 1976) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Mary Bickerton discusses her involvement in choir and service organizations, the campus dialogues surrounding feminism, and issues of race and class, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
    - Video interview with Marianne Bickerton
    - Transcript of interview with Marianne Bickerton (Box 3)
  - Sally Anderson Brush (Class of 1956) interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Sally Anderson Brush describes the campus atmosphere of Smith during the early 1950s, the lack of diversity and issues of race, and the expectation that one would marry. Brush also discusses her involvement with the crew team, the Christian Association, Judicial Board, her experiences as a religion major, her interactions with Gloria Steinem, and how Smith has impacted her life.
    - Video interview with Sally Anderson Brush
    - Transcript of interview with Sally Anderson Brush (Box 3)
  - Carolyn Carr (Class of 1961) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Carolyn Carr discusses her work within the Art department (including spending a summer studying art in Italy), how it affected her later career, her experiences taking a class with Sylvia Plath, and her transition to Smith from a small town in Virginia. Carr also describes issues of race and the Civil Rights Movement on campus, and her reaction to the Newton Arvin pornography scandal.
    - Video interview with Carolyn Carr
    - Transcript of interview with Carolyn Carr (Box 3)
  - Ann Christensen (Class of 1956) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Ann Christensen discusses how Smith shaped her as a person, what it was like adjusting to Smith coming from the South, issues of race and diversity, her experiences living in Haven House, and who she has become since attending Smith.
    - Video interview with Ann Christensen
    - Transcript of interview with Ann Christensen (Box 3)
  - Judith Snow Denison (Class of 1957) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Judy Denison describes her experiences living in Lawrence House as a scholarship student, her work as a physics major, her internship at the CERN, and her education after Smith. Denison also discusses her marriage and subsequent divorce, her children and grandchildren, and her job with the Bureau of the Census and recent work with the Belize Education Project.
    - Video interview with Judith Snow Denison
    - Transcript of interview with Judith Snow Denison (Box 3)
  - Carole DeSanti (Class of 1981) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Carole DeSanti describes why she decided to attend Smith and what it was like to adjust to the new atmosphere, her work as an English major, and her Marxist feminist philosophy. DeSanti also discusses the Lesbian Alliance and issues of sexuality, Hover House, reactions to the national press coverage of Smith in the early 1980s, and her opinion of President Conway.
    - Video interview with Carole DeSanti
    - Transcript of interview with Carole DeSanti (Box 3)
  - Katharine Esty (Class of 1956) interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Katharine Esty describes the political and social atmosphere at Smith during the McCarthy era, her experiences living in Jordan House and the divide between Jewish and non-Jewish students within the house, student protests regarding the Hungarian Revolution, the dating scene and how she met her husband at Amherst College, the lack of racial diversity within the student body, the impact that Betty Friedan's book The Feminine Mystique had on her, and her later work for UNICEF and as a psychotherapist.
    - Video interview with Katherine Esty
    - Transcript of interview with Katherine Esty (Box 3)
  - Susan Gesing (Class of 1961) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Susan Gesing describes what it was like arriving at Smith from the Midwest, what the dating scene and social atmosphere were like, her work as an American Studies major, her opinion on the Newton Arvin scandal, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
    - Video interview with Susan Gesing
    - Transcript of interview with Susan Gesing (Box 3)
  - Martha P. Grace (Class of 1961) interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Martha Grace discusses the overall atmosphere at Smith, her work as a zoology major, her experiences living in Dewey House, her marriage after her junior year, what a Smith education has meant to her, and her decision to attend law school and obtain a Masters degree in Animals and Public Policy.
    - Video interview with Martha P. Grace
    - Transcript of interview with Martha P. Grace (Box 3)
  - Group interview (Class of 1946) with Margaret Craig DeMott, Jane Hill, Rosalie Taylor Howlett, Helen Goddard, Abby Minot Gross, and Araxi Prévot, interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)